# callie gorman

#### calliegorman.design linkedin.com/in/calliegorman

calliegorman4@gmail.com 201-638-4568

#### **DESIGN SKILLS**

User Research

Competitive Analysis

**Usability Testing** 

Persona Creation

Sitemaps

User Stories/Flows

Sketching

Wireframing

Prototyping

Branding

Visual Design

#### **FRONTEND**

**HTML** 

CSS

Bootstrap

Javascript

jQuery

Github

#### **TOOLS**

Sketch

Figma

Invision

myBalsamiq

Draw.io

Illustrator

InDesign

### callie gorman. Digital Marketer turned Designer

## I am a UX Designer with 5+ years of experience marketing in the tech industry.

My education in psychology and past work as a digital marketer have taught me how to conduct effective user research, and therefore allows me to create intuitive designs that can increase user engagement rates to meet business goals.

#### RECENT PROJECTS

Led the UX process, including design creation, competitive and user research, and usability testing for:

#### vicarious

#### view prototype | view case study

A mobile travel app that prompts users to provides brief updates on each day of travel for family and friends.

#### connected

#### view prototype | view case study

A cloud-based storage application that features an intuitive interface, collaboration options, and dashboard personalization.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

#### **Digital Strategist**

Jan 2015 - Dec 2017

IBM Analytics, NYC | Remote

- Increased conversion rates by 2% on Analytics webpages by implementing A/B tests and recommending design changes
- Developed competitive analyses for brand teams that were utilized to update SEO keywords, web design layout, and copy
- Led strategy for 10+ quarterly digital campaigns that contributed more than \$1M of yearly marketing created revenue

#### Digital Lead

Dec 2016 - May 2017

#### Tribeca Film Festival, NYC | Remote

Developed digital and social media strategy for IBM / Tribeca Film Festival partnership, which drove 100+ customers to private sales events

#### Project Manager

Jan 2015 - April 2016

#### IBM Outthink Tour, NYC | Remote

Selected as lead project manager on a premiere event series, managing 10 teammates for events that drove 2000 net new clients

#### **LEADERSHIP**

#### **IBM Marketing Mentor**

Jan 2015 - May 2017

Chosen by managers to mentor five new employees during their onboarding

#### **EDUCATION**

#### UX/UI Design Program, Bloc

Dec 2017 - July 2018

Intensive user-centered design program building web and mobile app designs

#### College of the Holy Cross

May 2012

BA, Psychology, Pre-Business